ZACK POLLARD

1 The Pyghtle, Westoning, MK45 5LJ github.com/zackpollard \diamond git.zackpollard.pro

Mobile: 07928015705 \diamond Email: z.r.e.pollard-14@student.lboro.ac.uk

PROFILE

A second year BSc Computer Science student at Loughborough University. Systems Administrator and Programmer with 5 years of experience, through both freelance work and employment. Primarily works using Java with varied experience in other languages including C++, Python and PHP.

EDUCATION

Loughborough University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (1st Class)

· Dissertation: Secure Smart Lock System

Harlington Upper School

GCSE and Sixth Form

· A Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (B), ICT (C)

· Level 3 BTECs: Subsidiary Diploma in Sport (Distinction*)

- · 11 GCSES: Grades A* C in Mathematics, Advanced Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Business and Communication Systems, English Language, English Literature, Music, D&T Product Design and Religious Studies
- · Level 2 BTECs: OCR National First Certificate in ICT (Distinction) and Extended Certificate in Sport (Distinction*)

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM - iX Studios London

July 2016 - July 2017

Interactive Developer

Working directly with clients from Deutsche Bank and BP

Woodlands Middle School

Assistant Systems and Network Technician

July 2011 and July 2012 Flitwick, Bedfordshire

- · Provided technical support to users in a clear and concise manner.
- · Kept to a schedule and completed jobs within required deadlines.
- · Problem solving under pressure in time sensitive situations.
- · Worked effectively with members of a team to co-ordinate network repair tasks in order to prevent interference with users on the network.

Freelancing 2009 - Present

Java Development and Systems Administration

- · Dealing with clients requirements on a daily basis.
- · Managing time and providing accurate time frames for completion of projects.
- · Working as part of a team on projects utilising git for version control.
- · Persevering with problems to find acceptable solutions.

Loughborough, Leicestershire

September 2014 - July 2018

September 2009 - July 2014

 $Harlington,\ Bedfordshire$

Flitwick Cricket Club

Bartender - Part Time

April 2014 - January 2017 Flitwick, Bedfordshire

- · Dealing with customers and carrying out their requests accurately.
- · Working as part of a team, communicating with each other in order to keep everything running smoothly.
- · Keeping calm in high pressure situations such as large events.

KEY SKILLS AND BEHAVIOURS

- **Problem Solving:** Evident through freelance work that required an unconventional approach to solving problems introduced by client requirements.
- · Communication: This has been essential throughout all work in order to communicate with both clients and employers.
- **Time Management:** An essential skill demonstrated consistently during freelance work with a set time frame for completion.
- **Teamwork:** Demonstrated throughout many freelance projects and essential to ensure completion of tasks efficiently and before deadlines.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Java, C++, Python, Lua, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, AJAX

Data StructuresXML, JSON, YAMLDatabasesMySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools Git, Vim, Bash, Maven, Jenkins, LaTeX, KVM, SSH, VNC

Operating Systems CentOS 6/7 (Redhat), Debian, Arch (Arch)

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

SaxophoneABRSM Grade 8PianoABRSM Grade 6Music TheoryABRSM Grade 5

Kayaking & Canoe England BCU 2 Star

Full UK Clean Driving Licence

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- · Played the Saxophone and Piano for 10 and 12 years respectively.
- · Participated in various bands throughout Middle and Upper School and currently play in the University Jazz band, Tuxedo Swing.
- · Kayaking, Canoeing, Mountain Biking and Rock Climbing for 5 years.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.